[{"id": "5ffb58bd5dad637d903c8811", "question": "The Band-Aid supergroup was formed in 1984 to raise money for famine relief in what troubled African nation?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338911", "question": "What was the name of the cat in Walt Disney's movie \"Cinderella\"?", "answer": "Lucifer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5b", "question": "In 1995, Heather Whitestone became the first Miss America to have what disability?", "answer": "She was deaf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601737c944491cbd7c5a178e", "question": "What was the first national park in the U.S.?", "answer": "Yellowstone National Park -- Established on March 1, 1872, it is also widely recognized as the world's first national park.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062d1ac9d816e292245c31", "question": "What landmark work came about from a friend's request for a self-portrait of Rene Magritte?", "answer": "\"The Son of Man\"\u00a0(A friend's request for a self-portrait of Rene Magritte, which was a man's face obscured by a piece of fruit.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a6", "question": "What name did Nathaniel Dwayne Hale adopt, to hype his pedigree as Snoop Dogg's cousin?", "answer": "Nate Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339765", "question": "How does Kyra Collins die in the Sixth Sense?", "answer": "She is poisoned", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b86a", "question": "What is the Syrah grape called in Australia?", "answer": "Shiraz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7347aeec85e375820b235", "question": "Which US presidents signed the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson and John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399db", "question": "What 2005 Gwen Stefani song was the first single to amass one million paid digital downloads?", "answer": "Hollaback Girl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a70f", "question": "Which is the largest Great Lake?", "answer": "Lake Superior", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a169", "question": "In the film \"The Day of the Jackal\", who did Edward Fox play?", "answer": "Jackal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc8421e78d18506ae1fe48a", "question": "What is the name of the tallest tree in the world?", "answer": "Hyperion", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c795", "question": "What type of information does a DNA molecule carry?", "answer": "Genetic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d5", "question": "How many children did poet Sylvia Plath have?", "answer": "2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab3f", "question": "Juba is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "South Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133983f", "question": "Who was the first winner of the TV show \"America's Next Top Model\"?", "answer": "Adrianne Curry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c794", "question": "In science, what does the abbreviation DNA stand for?", "answer": "Deoxyribonucleic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d1", "question": "What year did Robert Burns write the poem \"Auld Lange Syne\"?", "answer": "1788", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5eb739095e259d7869087330", "question": "Which organ has 4 chambers?", "answer": "Heart", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb2", "question": "What item would a tailor measure in lignes?", "answer": "A button", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b279", "question": "What political party was led until 1985 by the brutal Pol Pot?", "answer": "The Khmer Rouge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133957d", "question": "The movie \"Best in Show\" was a mockumentary that examined a fictional what?", "answer": "Dog show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e08", "question": "What does Doctor Who's vast spacecraft, the TARDIS, look like from the outside?", "answer": "A police box", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c78", "question": "Which movie introduced Indiana Jones to the public?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392fc", "question": "In the movie \"True Romance\", what was the name of Clarence Worley's love interest?", "answer": "Alabama Whitman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca20", "question": "What are scaup?", "answer": "Ducks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a20c", "question": "What movie marked the first appearance of the mass murderer Jason Voorhees?", "answer": "Friday the 13th", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5b3d6ce05a3942286e13", "question": "Why did Vito Corleone flee Sicily?", "answer": "The local mafia, who had killed his parents and older brother, wanted him dead also.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d7", "question": "Who tore up a picture of the Pope on US television in 1992?", "answer": "Sinead O'Connor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cdbd5e347d002c297e4e2", "question": "What meteorological significance is traditionally attached to cows lying down?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59bb28a4c9bff04efae6d752", "question": "What massively successful novel did Mario Puzo publish in 1969?", "answer": "The Godfather", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d3", "question": "Which famous actor voiced characters Lovelace and Ramon in the movie \"Happy Feet\"?", "answer": "Robin Williams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b86", "question": "In the comic strip Peanuts, what color is Woodstock?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a3436c0f9723ab15cb4c", "question": "What event started the Great Depression?", "answer": "Black Tuesday", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339957", "question": "What was Mrs. Addams\u2019 first name on the TV show \"The Addams Family\"?", "answer": "Morticia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec26928dc25ca9e12ef64d", "question": "How many engines does the B-52 bomber have?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdd29ec223966ae8f8900", "question": "What band is the film \"Bohemian Rhapsody\" about?", "answer": "Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600399bb57a0e35c43f8389f", "question": "What German artist had Emperor Rudolph II as a patron?", "answer": "Hans von Aachen\u00a0-- He was one of the leading painters of Northern Mannerism and a painter of princely and\u00a0 aristocratic portraits.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa564ec73aa70ea0b70b29", "question": "What type of dancing is usually performed in conjunction with May Day celebrations in England?", "answer": "Morris dance", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c8", "question": "\"To swoon\" is to what?", "answer": "Faint", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a34", "question": "What movie western earned Gene Hackman his second acting Oscar?", "answer": "Unforgiven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff0", "question": "Where were fortune cookies invented?", "answer": "United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ac", "question": "In what city would you find Hyde Park?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58bb358fe368446ca7bd6854", "question": "What is an Affogato?", "answer": "Gelato, or ice cream, topped with hot espresso", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b57a", "question": "What popular soft drink was first created in Waco, Texas?", "answer": "Dr. Pepper", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cc7a877e98cb97778a26", "question": "Where was Breakneck Ridge in World War II?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d7", "question": "What extinct subspecies of zebra had stripes in front but a plain brown hindquarters?", "answer": "The quagga", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ded197ea2747c8aff16d34", "question": "Vodka and coffee liqueur make what cocktail?", "answer": "Black Russian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6c", "question": "Who is generally regarded as the inventor of the internal combustion automobile?", "answer": "Karl Benz", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c960", "question": "What name is given to a doctor who specializes in skin disorders?", "answer": "Dermatologist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab1c27baab681b0929219f", "question": "What car did Chevrolet design the Camaro to compete with in 1966?", "answer": "The Ford Mustang", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cbffa6de0eb824d4052d6", "question": "Where is the world's largest greenhouse?", "answer": "Cornwall, England -- The Eden Project is home to more than one million plants. It features two hexagonally-patterned biomes.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bebd", "question": "What day of the week is Mardi Gras?", "answer": "Tuesday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d92", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Artis Ivey?", "answer": "Coolio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff25b9c31a458464a93c479", "question": "What do people hang over their doors on New Year\u2019s Eve in Greece?", "answer": "Onions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a8", "question": "What nation was led by Rameses the Great?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067dbfff9c0647b50a8073", "question": "Which gaming franchise celebrated its 20th anniversary on February 27, 2016?", "answer": "Pokemon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc6", "question": "Who rode Rocinante?", "answer": "Don Quixote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb1", "question": "Which ingredient provides the red color in a Tequila Sunrise?", "answer": "Grenadine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339174", "question": "Who played Princess Leia in the original Star Wars movies?", "answer": "Carrie Fisher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5b525dad637d903c8819", "question": "In what city will you find Le Bourget Airport?", "answer": "Paris, France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56d", "question": "In what decade did scientists first split the atom?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fde4d8dc6c6b019850c9a81", "question": "The beautiful Nefertiti was the wife of what Pharaoh?", "answer": "Akhenaten", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b358ba05db0d66a186cb558", "question": "In architecture, what is a \"Purlin\"?", "answer": "A horizontal structural member", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5f95b05555722f97b22684dc", "question": "Who was the Hogwarts' headmaster right before Dumbledore?", "answer": "Armando Dippet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e8", "question": "What sport features snatches and clean jerks?", "answer": "Weightlifting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029f48cad1ec93f27df75e", "question": "Which empire gave the world the Pilsner?", "answer": "The Austrian Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a794", "question": "Port of Spain is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Trinidad and Tobago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b6cde662d71a5365100e", "question": "The book \"Lord of Light\", was written by whom?", "answer": "Roger Zelazny", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b43", "question": "What publication uses the motto \"America's Finest News Source\"?", "answer": "The Onion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac56", "question": "What landlocked European country remained neutral in both World Ware I and World War II?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ec7254857c9fcac0ce7197f", "question": "What is the scientific term for the tiger species?", "answer": "Panthera Tigris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c594", "question": "What is the alligator pear better known as?", "answer": "An avocado", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60121ab563c99d48cd169b06", "question": "What were clocks missing before 1577?", "answer": "Minute hands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c90a", "question": "Which continent is the natural habitat of the Ostrich?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c78a", "question": "What is the chemical formula for ozone?", "answer": "O3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fc25664865c716bd8505f26", "question": "While traveling on the original \"Oregon Trail\",' what were the five infectious diseases that killed many of the travelers?", "answer": "Cholera, Dysentery, Typhoid fever, Diphtheria, and Measles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338945", "question": "Which great painter's nickname translated literally to \"The Greek\"?", "answer": "El Greco", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f61", "question": "According to Dustin Hoffman in \"Rain Man\", what's the only airline that has never had a crash?", "answer": "Qantas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf9", "question": "What was the first building in the world to have more than 100 floors?", "answer": "Empire State Building", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dcb", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Woozy Winks?", "answer": "Plastic Man", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd68", "question": "On what Jewish holiday is the \"Kol Nidre\" prayer recited?", "answer": "Yom Kippur", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d1", "question": "Billed as \"The Crime of the Century\", in which US city did the Great Brink's Robbery take place, in 1950?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac25", "question": "Which country borders Suriname to the west?", "answer": "Guyana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071dc23745b36be73039dc", "question": "What is the nationality of the first woman in space?", "answer": "Soviet/Russian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac72", "question": "Between which two Ages did the Bronze Age occur?", "answer": "Stone and Iron Ages", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59bb28bdc9bff04efae6d753", "question": "What year was Mario Puzo's novel \"The Godfather\" published?", "answer": "1969", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392de", "question": "What new wave band recorded the 1978 album titled \"Parallel Lines\"?", "answer": "Blondie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a112", "question": "\"Dance with a Stranger\" was the film of who's life story?", "answer": "Ruth Ellis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f5", "question": "What actor played the role of Jean-Baptiste Emanuel Zorg in the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Gary Oldman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb04", "question": "Which member of the British royal family was married to Sarah Ferguson?", "answer": "Prince Andrew", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51d01ff04d658268c9321", "question": "In addition to his wife, who was seated with him when Abraham Lincoln was assassinated?", "answer": "Clara Harris and Henry Rathbone.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c16", "question": "The fictional town of South Park is located in which US state?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a68a", "question": "Lake Winnipesaukee is the largest lake in which US state?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65857ae7e414034b5aeed", "question": "What international organization was established at the end of World War I?", "answer": "League of Nations", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9eb", "question": "Cetology is the study of what?", "answer": "Whales, dolphins, and porpoise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a9e942c7ccba3ffe45786cf", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Californium?", "answer": "Cf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede2126ce05a3942286dcc", "question": "In 1996, Nintendo celebrated a milestone in the number of game cartridges sold with how many?", "answer": "One billion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339483", "question": "What powers Monstropolis in the movie \"Monsters, Inc.\"?", "answer": "Screams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60160173fe83fe1f2a824c5f", "question": "According to a famous Polish legend, which creature made a blanket to keep baby Jesus warm?", "answer": "A spider, which is why Poles have a great reverence for spiders.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e9", "question": "On what video game platform did the Gran Turismo game series debut?", "answer": "Playstation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe523411bf59ab7d2e380ee", "question": "Where was Winona Ryder caught shoplifting?", "answer": "Saks Fifth Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133937e", "question": "Where were the first Academy Awards held at?", "answer": "The Roosevelt Hotel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b8", "question": "What boxer appeared in the broadway musical \"Buck White\" in 1969?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c36", "question": "What year saw the end of the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "2004", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a0", "question": "How many gallons does a tun barrel typically hold?", "answer": "252", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133961e", "question": "Who starred as Colin Hanks' brother in the 2002 movie \"Orange County\"?", "answer": "Jack Black", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7b8", "question": "What year saw the launch of Heinz's tomato ketchup?", "answer": "1876", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f3", "question": "What type of food is Lollo Rosso?", "answer": "Lettuce", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a978", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Riksdag?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c734", "question": "Despite its name, what species of whale is most likely to die in mass strandings on the beach?", "answer": "Pilot whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d2", "question": "What is the English translation of the area of Cuba called Bahia de Cochinos?", "answer": "Bay of Pigs", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7e713b24f84e0b9f9ffb6", "question": "Who narrated the 1995 film \"Judge Dredd\"?", "answer": "James Earl Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339203", "question": "Who finds E.T.?", "answer": "Elliott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a4f", "question": "Little Red Riding Hood was called what in the original story by the Brothers Grimm?", "answer": "Little Red Cap", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a3", "question": "What mountain chain extends from western Canada down through Northern California?", "answer": "The Cascades", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e94", "question": "What Harry Potter snacks come in flavors including earwax, booger, and vomit?", "answer": "Bertie Bott's Every Flavor Beans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3eb", "question": "Who was the prime minister of Canada for the majority of Bill Clinton's time as U.S. President?", "answer": "Jean Chretien", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b12", "question": "What was the sub-title of the second Bridget Jones movie?", "answer": "The Edge of Reason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59d185823b17032616b590ff", "question": "When was Nescafe's instant coffee first launched?", "answer": "1938", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a1a2ff12f2a7826b9b8721", "question": "What French designer introduced the sack dress in the 1950's?", "answer": "Christian Dior", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baff", "question": "Edam, Jarlsberg, and Fontina are what types of food?", "answer": "Cheeses", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c09d", "question": "What wine barrel contains 252 gallons?", "answer": "Tun", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3ed7b8b5801b8f54a7fb2", "question": "When did the U.S. Postal Service release its first Christmas stamp?", "answer": "1962", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e6b5f9fb6c85e9e634ff46", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed \"Land of 10,000 Lakes\"?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae31", "question": "In 1972, who became the first American to win the world chess championship?", "answer": "Bobby Fischer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd9734b23c87fd04dd15e58", "question": "Who was the first person to single-handedly sail around the world?", "answer": "Joshua Slocum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ea", "question": "What are the two most common coffee bean types?", "answer": "Arabica and Robusta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c74b", "question": "When graphed, the implicit curve equation produces what shape?", "answer": "Heart", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd5e", "question": "What cut of beef, often used for hamburger, is also called the \"seven-bone steak\"?", "answer": "Chuck steak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59068076ff9c0647b50a808c", "question": "At what age did Prince release his debut album \"For You\"?", "answer": "19", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d54", "question": "What famous double negative is the first line in Pink Floyd's \"Another Brick in the Wall (Part II)\"?", "answer": "We don't need no education", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b23", "question": "What book was Mark David Chapman carrying when he shot John Lennon?", "answer": "The Catcher in the Rye", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4d9a9f08b8581f80b092be", "question": "Whose concert was the target of a terrorist attack in May, 2017, in Manchester, UK?", "answer": "Ariana Grande\u2019s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea49d6ff048f679a45abbc", "question": "What part of the plant gets water and nutrients to the rest of the plant?", "answer": "Stem", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ec1", "question": "What animal's head appears on the handle of Mary Poppins' umbrella?", "answer": "A parrot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea2", "question": "Who was the first man to swim the English channel?", "answer": "Captain Mathew Webb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9c", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Dr. Strangelove\"?", "answer": "Peter Sellers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339563", "question": "Bill Melendez directed which Christmas TV special?", "answer": "A Charlie Brown Christmas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f747fa9e54d890926f6f8", "question": "What is the name for the monetary unit used in Thailand?", "answer": "Thai Bhat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339243", "question": "What is the main character's job in the movie \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "Archeologist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339be3", "question": "In what year was actor Johnny Depp born?", "answer": "1963", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e2b", "question": "Who ferries the dead across the river Acheron in Greek mythology?", "answer": "Charon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f2", "question": "What sport in the Olympics includes tucks, twists and pikes?", "answer": "Diving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe52e0c1bf59ab7d2e3810f", "question": "While presenting the first iPhone, Steve Jobs prank called what company?", "answer": "Starbucks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d6", "question": "Which chemical element has the atomic number 4?", "answer": "Beryllium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65612ae7e414034b5aebf", "question": "The goddess Artemis was known as the Mistress of what?", "answer": "Animals", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbc", "question": "What model was married to musician Mick Jagger?", "answer": "Jerry Hall", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393de", "question": "In what year did Elton John release his single \"Crocodile Rock\"?", "answer": "1973", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc262ec223966ae8f8874", "question": "What movie star uses his middle initial, B, for \"Bakari\", to avoid confusion with a retired basketball star?", "answer": "Michael B. Jordan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa56d6ce05a3942286ec0", "question": "In the film \"Silence of the Lambs,\" whose head does Hannibal Lector say is in the jar Clarice finds?", "answer": "Benjamin Raspail", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff213af31a458464a93c451", "question": "Pineapples, kiwis and papayas contain enzymes that can do what to meat?", "answer": "Tenderize it", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a59d", "question": "What US state's southern border is marked by the original Mason Dixon Line?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5cc", "question": "Concord is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339463", "question": "Who played Butch Cassidy?", "answer": "Paul Newman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe771a2eec85e375820b2fb", "question": "What does a flower worn behind a woman's right ear mean in Hawaii?", "answer": "She's single", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58a0f5ea732c90c4fd3069cf", "question": "Who was the childhood playmate of little Jackie Papers?", "answer": "Puff, the Magic Dragon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9bb62364247bf200fb8a3", "question": "Who was disqualified after winning the 1976 British Grand Prix?", "answer": "James Hunt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339296", "question": "What is the most common swear word used in the TV series \"Battlestar Galactica\"?", "answer": "Frak", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca53", "question": "The rate of change of velocity is known as what?", "answer": "Acceleration", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f16a79f7c52aae91cc07dd", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\", who is the Kind of Naples?", "answer": "Alonso", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9047001dd7bf43be5e875", "question": "What can a polyglot do?", "answer": "Know and speak several languages", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600240ef4be4723ccac2216c", "question": "In the novel \"Dances with Wolves\", what is the name of the outpost Lieutenant Dunbar is assigned?", "answer": "Fort Sedgwick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ee0606d333868d34d772", "question": "Where can you find the world\u2019s longest-operating \"Santa School\"?", "answer": "Midland, Michigan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc13f5469bb8041d07a082", "question": "Something that is toward the end or away from the center of the body can also be called what?", "answer": "Distal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefbe546ce05a3942286eed", "question": "Which actor had a role in the Hannibal Lector films \"Manhunter,\" \"Silence of the Lambs,\" \"Hannibal\" and \"Red Dragon\"?", "answer": "Frankie Faison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d07753870e6f05ba600862", "question": "Who composed the title music to TV's \"Inspector Morse\"?", "answer": "Barrington Pheloung", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a028", "question": "Which \"Family Guy\" character war married to Loretta?", "answer": "Cleveland Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aefb", "question": "What American outlaw went by such names as Kid Antrim, Henry McCarty and William Bonney?", "answer": "Billy the Kid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa5", "question": "Which famous artist was shot and wounded by Valerie Solanas In 1968?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c901", "question": "What word, beginning with M, is the unit measurement for the brightness of stars?", "answer": "Magnitude", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd81ce2d0de9af39e9d4689", "question": "How many official copies of the Bill of Rights were originally made?", "answer": "14", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab1b2544fda37788a9a1db8", "question": "What is the capital of Burkina Faso?", "answer": "Ouagadougou", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf3", "question": "What two things are being compared in a stock's \"P/E ratio\"?", "answer": "Share price and earnings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b863", "question": "What is the highest possible bowling score in a game with no strikes?", "answer": "190", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c457", "question": "Whose \"Difference Engine\" is often described as the first computer?", "answer": "Charles Babbage's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397b4", "question": "What wise guys are forever linked to the phrase: \"Nyuk, nyuk, nyuk\"?", "answer": "The 3 Stooges", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47e", "question": "What is the capital of Vermont?", "answer": "Montpelier", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b571c8667df192a942e3375", "question": "Who is Edson Arantes do Nascimento more widely known as?", "answer": "Pele", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c564", "question": "What name is given to a main downward-growing root of a plant?", "answer": "Taproot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acab", "question": "What month in 1912 saw the Titanic go down?", "answer": "April", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d8", "question": "What element combines with sodium to make ordinary table salt?", "answer": "Chlorine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecce80ec223966ae8f88b0", "question": "Who did not attend the 1977 premiere of \"Star Wars: A New Hope\"?", "answer": "George Lucas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb7", "question": "What is the name of Alan's ex-wife on the TV show \"Two and a Half Men\"?", "answer": "Judith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69bc320565ad31a57c764", "question": "Who was the last king of Troy in Greek mythology?", "answer": "Priam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c4a6fbde8045e484669f", "question": "Which small African mammal keeps a watch-duty rotation throughout the day?", "answer": "Meerkat -- One, called the sentry, will keep a watch for predators by standing on its hind legs.  They rotate who is on watch.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59636b0e967692ea851899a2", "question": "Which \"Committee of Five\" member was the only one to sign all four of the US state papers?", "answer": "Roger Sherman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b04f", "question": "What holiday was first celebrated in Spokane, Washington on June 19, 1910?", "answer": "Father's Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339284", "question": "What coach's team won the first challenge in season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Britney's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc854c9abc30a8194e188aa", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Perfect Storm\"?", "answer": "Sebastian Junger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010c7e20775fa611bce67dd", "question": "Why do penny loafers have a slot for a coin?", "answer": "For a payphone -- Penny loafers allowed schoolchildren to always have two pennies if they needed to make an emergency call home.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d267bb53d1af65886509", "question": "Candy canes are said to have originated from which European country?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b305", "question": "How did Ponce de Leon, Claudius, and Tycho Brahe all die?", "answer": "They were poisoned", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae7f", "question": "What nickname was given to President Andrew Jackson?", "answer": "Old Hickory", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b47c", "question": "What year did the Battle of the Plains of Abraham take place?", "answer": "1759", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c368", "question": "What acid gives citrus fruits their distinctive sharp flavor?", "answer": "Citric acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd1", "question": "What TV show did \"Mork and Mindy\" spin off from?", "answer": "Happy Days", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd14", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal whose mascot was CinnaMon?", "answer": "Apple Jacks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b57187367df192a942e335f", "question": "Tierra del Fuego is divided between which two South American countries?", "answer": "Chile and Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b55f", "question": "What was the first soft drink to be consumed in outer space?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c578fbde8045e48466ad", "question": "A group of otters is called what?", "answer": "A raft", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a90", "question": "Dr. Brown's puppy in \"Back to the Future Part II\" was named after what astronomer?", "answer": "Copernicus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc51", "question": "What year was Marmite first launched onto the market?", "answer": "1902", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfdde9616e6c6d4eba4f9", "question": "What is the plural of the word \"crisis\"?", "answer": "Crises", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b73b", "question": "Retsina is a wine traditionally made in which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba59f874c93a3298b2152", "question": "What talk show has Chris Hardwick hosted on AMC immediatley following the TV show \"The Walking Dead\"?", "answer": "The Talking Dead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ea0608d98002fdd6339e", "question": "Which Stephen King novel is set at the \"Overlook Hotel\"?", "answer": "The Shining", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fe", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman goddess Venus?", "answer": "Aphrodite", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59c1cddf7bd84c0ea43ad430", "question": "In Norse mythology Odin traded an eye for what?", "answer": "Wisdom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69e3620565ad31a57c780", "question": "What was the real name of the Confederate ironclad ship that went to battle with the USS Monitor?", "answer": "CSS Virginia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b8", "question": "The Province of Saskatchewan shares its southern border with which two US states?", "answer": "Montana and North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3db", "question": "What company introduced the first transistor-based hearing aid?", "answer": "Zenith", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca38", "question": "Which element is fourth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Beryllium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a350", "question": "What Russian city boasts the Hermitage Museum?", "answer": "St. Petersburg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e7", "question": "Which country of Europe is called the land of humane bullfights: where the bulls are not killed?", "answer": "Portugal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592ead3ff83302ff91e46478", "question": "The fear of learning is known as what?", "answer": "Sophophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e9f", "question": "What is the \"Pale Blue Dot\" in the title of Carl Sagan's 1994 book?", "answer": "Earth, as seen from space", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cddb5e347d002c297e4f3", "question": "Which 1960s singer/songwriter was voted \"Ugliest Man on Campus\" while attending college?", "answer": "Janis Joplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05d", "question": "What is the name of the genetically modified dinosaur in the 2015 movie \"Jurassic World\"?", "answer": "Indominus Rex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d084a1a1c922dd1ac64c2", "question": "In the opera, what kind of factory did Carmen work in?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4f", "question": "What LSU Tiger was drafted by the Orlando Magic in 1992?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015ecfefe83fe1f2a824c06", "question": "How many times are Jews supposed to wash their hands at the Seder table?", "answer": "Two times", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefbea56ce05a3942286ef4", "question": "Which rock band performed at President Bill Clinton's first inauguration?", "answer": "Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe658b7ae7e414034b5aef6", "question": "Who were the two leaders of Chile's Independence movement from 1810 until 1818?", "answer": "Bernardo O'Higgins And Jose De San Martin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b31a", "question": "Who was the first man to appear on the cover of Playboy Magazine?", "answer": "Peter Sellers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d4749bf8e329de4f87789e", "question": "In what year did Margaret Thatcher assume office as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1979", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce4", "question": "Which \"Friends\" character is the answer to the trivia question in the SNL \"Lazy Sunday\" sketch?", "answer": "Matthew Perry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5eb73c6b5e259d7869087331", "question": "Who was the designer of the Lincoln penny coin?", "answer": "Victor David Brenner", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e38d71ef6c8a670a7957c5c", "question": "What South American city\u2019s citizens are known as \"Cariocas\"?", "answer": "Rio de Janiero", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59da1b31f6756c9b30ba14f6", "question": "On which river is the city of Mandalay situated?", "answer": "Irrawaddy River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133905d", "question": "What year did poet Sylvia Plath die?", "answer": "1963", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b019", "question": "Prior to Ronald Reagan, who was the last US president whose first and last name began with the same letter?", "answer": "Herbert Hoover", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c80dfbde8045e48466cd", "question": "Tercel is the name for the male of which animal?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c45e", "question": "What is mixed with clay, baked in a kiln, and then pulverized in order to make Portland cement?", "answer": "Limestone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe93d576bd93ce3a4e5f6b4", "question": "What type of rock is formed by consolidation of molten magma?", "answer": "Igneous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acfc", "question": "What wiped out Napoleon's Caribbean troops, leading him to scrap plans to conquer the New World?", "answer": "Yellow Fever", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cdbe9e347d002c297e4e3", "question": "Who was known as the King of Pop?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b784", "question": "Who invented machine-spun cotton candy?", "answer": "William Morrison", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b7abbd76490a8cc1a6e5298", "question": "What is the maximum number of points one can achieve in the video game \"Pac-Man\"?", "answer": "3,333,360 points", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a63a", "question": "West Virginia has a shoreline along which ocean?", "answer": "None", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015fbdafe83fe1f2a824c3d", "question": "In the latter 19th century, which now-common Valentine's Day practice was considered bad luck?", "answer": "Signing Valentine's cards -- Reportedly, some people still refuse to sign Valentines Day cards using their own name.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cc7fbb53d1af658864e1", "question": "Who created Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer?", "answer": "Robert Lewis May", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e1", "question": "What was the better known nickname of 19th century figure Joseph Merrick?", "answer": "The Elephant Man", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f565ef33a95c66dc4fe75c", "question": "Bismarck is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c114", "question": "What year was Canadian figure skater, Elvis Stojko, born?", "answer": "1972", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c29", "question": "What instrument did Dizzy Gillespie play?", "answer": "Trumpet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3c", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"The Shifting Reef\"?", "answer": "20,000 Leagues Under the Sea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab6", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Finland?", "answer": "Whooper swan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e5", "question": "Why did the Simpsons go to New York CIty?", "answer": "Retrieve a lost car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d43", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Alien 3\"?", "answer": "Sigourney Weaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b759", "question": "The two-cent piece was the first US coin to feature which phrase?", "answer": "In God We Trust", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb57b35dad637d903c880a", "question": "What material did early Venetians use to construct the foundations of their buildings?", "answer": "Wood (Venice's buildings were built on marshy mud and sand.  The wood petrified due to the lack of oxygen in the marshy soil.)", "category": "geography"}]